<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cong Pham</title>
    <description>Cong Pham's official portfolio site. A collection of carefully curated and up-to-date works.
</description>
    <link>http://congphamdesign.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://congphamdesign.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 23:00:03 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 23:00:03 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Front-end Development Works</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://misfit.com/campaign/lumenati/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/front-end-works/front-end-misfit-lumenati-sxsw.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://misfit.com/wheretobuy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/front-end-works/front-end-misfit-where-to-buy.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/front-end-works/front-end-misfit-mothersday.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/front-end-works/front-end-misfit-mothersday-mobile-3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/front-end-works/front-end-misfit-referral.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://congphamdesign.com/coding/front-end-dev/2015/06/27/front-end-works.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://congphamdesign.com/coding/front-end-dev/2015/06/27/front-end-works.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>front-end-dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Condor Typeface</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Condor Typeface is created with one important goal, to celebrate the love for Vietnamese language. Condor is a side project I have quickly crafted after my trip away for a weekend, where I’ve encountered numerous vinage on abandoned and old buildings.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Vietnamese language is drifting far away from its aesthetic. I took the risk of stating that for a few reasons. Firstly, right now around the cities, hand painted signs from the pre-war period are disappearing. They are being replaced with digital printed canvas that was crafted using a world processor, sometimes vector based tools like Illustrator or Corel but just for the sake of getting-the-job-done. The quality is extremely bad. The aesthetic is missing. The layout is crooked. Good signage is heading toward becoming a lost art, a near extinct creature crippling in this society. Secondly, the places that has beautiful signage, carefully crafted branding, tend to not be in Vietnamese. They were Vietnamese stores, restaurants or event halls, but preferably chosen English or foreign language name. Talks’ve been spilled that the Vietnamese language with its diacritical marks usually an obstacle for beauty and asthetic. Lastly, combining the above reason, we have people either not care to use a product with Vietnamese writing on them or prefer not to include Vietnamese in their brands people they afraid no one will like it.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Let’s talk about the inspiration for this typeface. I visited Côn Đảo island back in June 2015. Côn Đảo is like Alcatraz, for those of you don’t know Alcatraz, it’s a prison, on an island, that doesn’t have civilian. Well, Côn Đảo was used before and during the wars in Vietnam, lasted for more than 100 years. During those years, rumours had it that the prisoners were treated terribly, without any sort of human rights. Then after the war it was abandoned and closed down by the government. Now the place is perfectly preserved of its former state and is opened for tourists from all over the war. I was not as fascinated with the stories there as with the signages found there. All of the old signage were in beautiful typograhy, the camp’s sign (i.e. Camp I, Camp II, etc.). And all of those were in Vietnamese, with beautifully crafted diacritical marks. It seems like before the war the people actually value this language. That was when I had the idea of designing a typeface from the signages I have found on Côn Đảo.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Condor is a display typeface. Its usage would suit most with signage because of its block letters, almost monospaced. The subtle contrast between stroke weight makes it legible when seeing a far and its spacious counter makes it less claustrophobic when put together. The diacritics are much thinner creating big contrast with the letter yet less obstrusive and still focus on the aesthetical form of the letters. The Condor is best when typeset on one line, usually a name of a brand or a place. But when shown in multiple lines, the typeface is possible to provide great visual depends on the creativity of your layout.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Right now, Condor is still in its last phrase of developement and will probably be distributed for free soon. If you want to keep up to date with the progress, check back here often or shoot me an &lt;a class=&quot;primary-color&quot; href=&quot;mailto:me@congphamdesign.com&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; and I will send out mass email when it’s ready.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://congphamdesign.com/design/typeface/2015/06/25/condor-typeface.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://congphamdesign.com/design/typeface/2015/06/25/condor-typeface.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>typeface</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
